Contact

ebiersdorfer@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ebiersdorfer (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Surgery

Certifications

Cerner Fundementals

Health Informatics Curriculum and Training for Transformation

Registered Nurse

Project Management Essentials

ERIC BIERSDORFER, BSN, RN

Interventional Radiology and Diagnostics Nurse Manager at CHI St. Luke's Health

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

As you review this profile you will notice my vast experience. I believe this is a enhance quality that allows me to adapt to any position or situation. My experience allows me to relate and understand a variety of issue and communicate with almost any department or specialty with clarity. I am a quick learner, good listener and thoughtful responder to issues and projects that arise. You will see a ROI quickly when allowing me to work with your organization.

Experience

CHI St. Luke's Health - Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center 2 years 2 months

Interventional Radiology and Diagnostics Nurse Manager November 2019 - Present (9 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Neuro Service Line Manager June 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 6 months) Houston, Texas

Oversee 20 bed ICU and 29 bed step down unit in a Magnet, Comprehensive Stroke Certified Hospital.

Memorial Hermann Health System

7 years 11 months

Operations Supervisor November 2019 - Present (9 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Katy, Texas

Critical Care RN May 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Page 1 of 5

Float Pool RN with roles in PACU, ICU, IMU, SWAT, ED AND OA.

Physician CSA - Enterprise Physician Initiatives March 2014 - May 2018 (4 years 3 months) Katy

Increased CPOE Scores for Meaningful Use 10% and Still Raising Bar Each Year, Number One in System for 2 Years

Establish Working Rapport with over Four Hundred Physicians and Ensure Their Compliance with EMR Initiatives

Educate New Physicians on EMR Platform and Assist in Developing Efficient Workflows Based on Specialty

Analyze, Design, Configure, Test, Implement and Support Cerner's PowerChart EMR Applications On Site

RN II

September 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 1 month) Medical Center Level I Neuro Trauma ICU

Direct External Ventricular Device Placement and Management, Vigileo Set up, Placement and Monitoring, Hyper/Hypothermia System Set up and Management

Cypress Fairbanks Medical Center Hospital 3 years

House Supervisor September 2016 - July 2018 (1 year 11 months) Houston, Texas Area

Oversee Patient throughput via ED, Direct Admits and Transfers In and Out of Hospital at a Level II Trauma Center

Respond to Patient/Family/Staff Issues that Arise Throughout the Various Departments

Assist Physicians in Scheduling Emergency Procedures and Ensure Staffing Available for Procedure

Ensure Proper Staffing Based on Acuity and Census for Current Shift and Upcoming Shift

Supervise up to Sixty Plus Staff Members and Report Daily to C-Suite Members

RN PACU

August 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 1 month)

Cypress, Texas

Attended to Recovering Patients Post Emergency Surgery Related To Trauma, OB or other Emergent Complications

ProHealth Staffing

Travel RN

June 2008 - July 2018 (10 years 2 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Work at a Variety of Ambulatory Surgical Centers, Pain Management,

Orthopedics, Plastic Surgery, and ENT

Implement Multiple Changes for Efficiency and Patient Safety at Several of the Facilities

During Charge Nurse Duties, Oversaw up to Fifteen Nurses and other Ancillary Staff, While Managing Throughput of up to Sixty Patients, Directly Reported to Director of Nursing Daily on Production Flow

The Right Solutions

Critical Care RN

August 2007 - July 2018 (11 years)

Houston, Texas Area

Adapt to ER's, ICU's and Telemetry Units at Various Facilities in and Around Houston and Surrounding Areas

Manage Up to 8 Patients in a Given Shift with Co-Morbidities and High Acuities.

Spring Central Hospital

PACU Charge RN / ED RN

November 2013 - March 2014 (5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Assessed, Instructed and Discharged Orthopedic, GYN, Plastic, Endo, General and Pain Management Patients

Participated in Environment of Care Committee to Access Hospital

Environment

Assisted Staff and Physicians in Accessing and Navigating EMR

Created Weekly and Daily Staffing Schedules and Implemented Staggered

Flow for PreOp and PACU Staff

Oversaw ER Daily Routine as Single Nurse with Secretary and Paramedic

Assistance

Training of Physicians and Co-Workers on EMR.

Altus Infusion

Charge Nurse

April 2013 - November 2013 (8 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Within Three Months of Management, Increased Patient Census by over 100% Managed Upwards of 200+ Patients in Infusion Suite Setting Collaborated with Physician to Ensure Proper Treatment Based on Labs,

Oversaw All Business and Clinical Aspects of Infusion Suite

Houston Arthritis Associates, PA Clincial Triage Nurse Manager April 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Clinical Symptoms and Patient Assessment

Houston, Texas Area

Oversaw the Daily Practice of Two Rheumatologists, Including Triaging Calls, Supervising Three Plus Staff

Performed Bone Dexa Studies as Ordered, Assisted in Phlebotomy and IV Access in Infusion Suite when Needed

Assisted in Implementing New Electronic Health Records System and Developing Practice Specific Template's

Methodist Willowbrook RN II

January 2011 - April 2011 (4 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Active in Unit-Based Education Committee, Distributed Materials and Educated Staff Regarding Practice Changes

Medical Infusion Therapy
Director Of Nursing
March 2010 - February 2011 (1 year)

Houston, Texas Area

Worked Per diem until 9/1/2010 when I became the Nurse Manager

Supervised a Staff of up to Eight RNs and LVNs, Reported Directly to CEO/ President Weekly

Performed Recruiting Duties and Training of All Nursing Staff Including Chart Audits and Performance Evaluations

Analyzed Call Center Data, Evaluated and Interpreted Statistical Reports to include QM, Medical Necessity, Location of Care and Length of Treatmen, Drafted Policy and Procedures Relevant to Current Nursing Standards of Care/Practice

Developed Response and Action Plan in retort to TJC Evaluation

Kirby Surgical Center Critical Care RN March 2010 - July 2010 (5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Pre-Screened Patients for Medical Clearance Prior to Surgical Procedures Ensured Patient is Properly Educated Prior to Surgical Procedure and at Discharge

intrafusion Nurse Manager December 2008 - March 2010 (1 year 4 months) Houston, Texas Area

Communicated with Physicians Regarding Lab Results, Plan of Treatment, Reactions and Tolerance

Educated Patients Regarding Home Self-Infusion Therapy and Arranged for Discharge of Patients from Hospital

Verified Appropriate Insurance Information and Medical Records to Assist in Approval of Benefits

Responsible for Pharmacy Technician and Coordinating Schedules with Staff, Directly Reported to Vice President

Education

Texas A&M University BS, Food Science · (1996 - 2002)

The University of Texas at Arlington RN-BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2012 - 2013)

Lonestar College - Tomball ADN, LVN, RN · (2006 - 2010)